KINJAL PARAS MEHTA

Boston, MA 02120 | 857-800-3479 | kinjalpm96@gmail.com | Portfolio: https://www.kinjalmehta.me/ | LinkedIn: https://www.kinjalmehta.me/ | GitHub: https://github.com/KinjalPM |

SUMMARY

A goal-oriented and solution-driven software enthusiast graduate student having co-op experience as a Web Developer. I have attended events like the GHC 2020 and TechToegther (Hackathon) 2019. I solve each challenge as an opportunity aimed at contributing constructively to the society with effective communication. My skill set includes Java, JavaScript, React.js, Spring-Boot, and Mysql. Looking forward to explore in professional stimulating environments.

EDUCATION

Northeastern University, Boston, MA

Sep 2018 - Dec 2020

Master of Science in Information Systems

Related Courses: Web Development Tools & Methods, Web Design/User Experience, Program Structure & Algorithms, User Experience Design/Testing, Advanced Big Data Indexing, and Software Quality Control & Mgmt

University of Mumbai, Mumbai, India

Aug 2014 - May 2018

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics Engineering

Related Courses: Object Oriented Programming (Java), C, Management Information Systems

TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

Back-End Technologies Java, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Servlets, REST, NodeJS

Front-End Technologies JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, Sass, AngularJS

Frameworks/Libraries React.JS, jQuery, Bootstrap4
Wireframe Tools Moqups, Balsamiq, InVision
Databases MySOL, MongoDB

IDE Microsoft Visual Studio, NetBeans 8.2, MySQL Workbench, Eclipse IDE

VC Tools GitHub, Bitbucket

WORK EXPERIENCE

Oxfam America, Boston, MA

Web Developer Intern

Jan 2020 - Jul 2020

- Automated database with HubSpot & leveraged Nodejs for CURD to enhance productivity of email marketing
- Designed several templates via JavaScript, HTML, and CSS for email marketing targeting a vast range of audience
- Collaborated with teams globally and worked on various assignments to complete different challenges
- Scrutinized user research and created reports for better accessibility of company website
- Built various forms for social cause including fundraisers
- Resolved various ad-hoc issues from cross-functional teams
- Performed several Quality Assurance tests on development side and deployed code on Heroku platform

University of Mumbai, Mumbai, India

IoT Intern

Jan 2018 – Apr 2018

- Devised and performed Automatic Street Light project
- Automated streetlights based on threshold levels using arduino processor, light sensor, and LEDs were used to
- Assembled data on ThingSpeak through Wi-Fi module for street-light maintenance

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Grocery Management System (Hibernate, Spring MVC, MySQL, JSP, Apache Tomcat)

Jan 2019 – Apr 2019

- Implemented features such as login page, cart and checkout page for customers
- Managed data of customers, transactions details and stock inventory in tables with hibernate and MySQL
- Created front-end for entire website using JSP

The Entertainment World (JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Mongo DB, Visual Studio, Node.js)

Jan 2019 - Apr 2019

- Collaborated with web design team to redesign a website to collect reviews of media products
- Accomplished imbedding movie trailer on website through iframe
- Executed payment for customer subscription leveraging PayPal Sandbox
- Collected and organized movie & television ratings and reviews via Mongo DB to enhance customer engagement

City Crime Management Java Application (Java, Java Swing, NetBeans 8.2)

Sep 2018 -Dec 2018

- Developed Crime Management System application in Swing where citizens can directly & anonymously report crime
- Simulated application by applying an ecosystem model & singleton design pattern
- Utilized date chooser and Java-Mail API for choosing date and mailing system
- Evaluated on complete, pending & unassigned cases to achieve 30% optimization by implementing pie charts

Hospital Database Management System (MySQL, ERD, MySQL Workbench)

Sep 2018 - Dec 2018

- Resolved data management problem by efficiently applying data queries to handle database
- Built schema based on entity- relationship diagram with minimum data redundancy
- Improved user performance by 20 % by creating trigger, stored procedure and joints
- Analyzed revenue generated by hospital and different departments by persistent querying on database